<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research | Chashi Mahiul Islam</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Research</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu68170e94a17a2a43d6dcb45cf0e8e589_3079_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Visual Spatial Reasoning through Multi-Task Learning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/visual_spatial_reasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/visual_spatial_reasoning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed a vision-language model incorporating spatial features like depth maps, 3D coordinates, and edge maps through multi-task learning, improving spatial understanding and achieving state-of-the-art results on the Visual Spatial Reasoning (VSR) dataset.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Attacks on Aligned Large Language Models</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/llm_adversarial_attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/llm_adversarial_attack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed a novel adversarial attack technique for Large Language Models, leveraging regularized gradients with continuous optimization to generate valid tokens and significantly improve attack efficiency and success rates&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adversarial Exploitation in Robot Vision-Language Navigation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/path_manipulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/path_manipulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed a novel algorithm to adversarially modify images, exploiting the semantic representation gaps in vision-language models, enabling controlled redirection of robot navigation paths through minimal image alterations. Improved security through a detection mechanism sensitive to noise in manipulated images.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inherent Vulnerabilities of Vision Transformers for Medical Image Classification</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/medical_image_adversarial_attack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/medical_image_adversarial_attack/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Explored vulnerabilities in vision transformers for medical image classification, demonstrating that minor modifications can significantly alter representations, and developed an efficient detection method to enhance model reliability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimodal Classification with LLMs - Unstructured Text Feature Extraction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/multimodal_classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/multimodal_classification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developing text data processing pipelines with private large language models to extract meaningful features with in-context reasoning and developing fusion models to improve classification scores by combining unstructured and tabular data in multimodal settings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Superresolution for Enhanced Analysis of Low-Resolution Content</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/super_resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/super_resolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Evaluated SOTA models for identifying low-resolution deep fakes in collected videos, and enhanced low-resolution deep fake detection, resulting in up to 19% test accuracy improvement on FaceShifter dataset using Xception Net.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval of Brain Tumor with Region Based Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/brain_tumor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/brain_tumor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed an automated brain tumor image segmentation pipeline, incorporating Anisotropic Filtering for denoising, contrast
enhancement, and skull removal, resulting in a remarkable 11.58% increase in precision and a minor 0.1% accuracy
improvement when compared to the state-of-the-art method for brain tumor segmentation employing adaptive filtering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval of Brain Tumor with Region Based Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/vit_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/vit_analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developed an automated brain tumor image segmentation pipeline, incorporating Anisotropic Filtering for denoising, contrast
enhancement, and skull removal, resulting in a remarkable 11.58% increase in precision and a minor 0.1% accuracy
improvement when compared to the state-of-the-art method for brain tumor segmentation employing adaptive filtering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
